Giulia Mummolo

mail@giuliamummolo.com (+44) 07426490423 London - UK

Experienced e-commerce executive with solid retail experience built in 7 years within different roles across sales and with a strong focus on product and client experience across several areas of the fashion industry. I have translated the knowledge acquired in direct contact with the consumer into the digital e-commerce by closely working with different teams across the business such as creative, marketing and tech. As personal interest towards innovative technologies, I have been actively taking part in web re-development which lead me to further build my personal skills by completing a full stack coding boot-camp. My strong analytical skills combined with my creative approach have been leading me to explore different ways for problem solving and to seek for new opportunities to further develop my career in e-commerce.



EXPERIENCE

Georgiana Scott

E-Commerce Executive (February 2019 - Present)

Managed E-Commerce restructure projects across product, design, SEO and digital marketing and improved client engagement and retain strategy through site optimisation and digital campaigns across different media channels such as digital marketing and social media advertising campaigns.

Developed a strategic product planning and management of products cycle across the brand's website.

Responsible for site analytics, data driven strategic planning. Managing third party e-commerce partners and maintaining relations with international manufactures and wholesale accounts including independent retailers and department stores.

- Planned and executed marketing campaigns which doubled total page views
- Re-designed website which improved bounce rate by 20%

Shopify • Klaviyo Marketing • Mailchimp • Unleashed Management • Google Analytics • Facebook Ads • Google PPC Ads

Moncler

Sales Product Major (January 2017 - February 2018)

First point of contact for Moncler own products within the Harrods concession, managing product cycle including stock maintenance, movements across Europe, after care services and customers enquiries liaising with operations and sales teams to maximise business revenue and maintaining luxury service expectations and presence across the market. Developed innovative merchandising approaches with Regional Visual Merchandisers and reporting implementations

- · Managed transition from wholesale to retail
- Managed a team of four providing mentoring and business trainings
- · Consumer data collection and reporting to Buying and Merchandising teams for development of upcoming collections

SAP: Inventory Management • CBR: Retail POS • Adyen payments • Microsoft Excel

Harrods

Brand Manager (May 2015 - January 2017)

Part-Time role covered while completing my BA degree course and promoted to Full-Time after graduating. Responsible for the overall performance within the luxury Childrenswear division with a main focus for outerwear products following brand's vision and guidelines

Created a brand strategy following an in depth market and competitors analysis: forecasting consumer's behaviour and accordingly develop marketing campaigns, planning of consumer focused events to drive sales across the department.

- Increased the revenue of the assigned department by 40% exceeding business KPIs expectations such as UPT and ATV
- Decreased stock loss across the department by 20% and responsible for loss prevention trainings

Bottega Veneta

Private Client Advisor and Visual Merchandiser (September 2014 - April 2015)

Part-Time role covered while completing my BA degree course.

Banana Republic

Store Supervisor (May 2012 - August 2014)

Part-Time role covered while completing my BA degree course.

Supervised a team of 20 across several roles within a KPIs performance based environment.



EDUCATION

Kodiri

Coding Bootcamp (August - October 2019)

Intensive full-stack course on programming on most demanding stack in IT industry.

Development of professional grade web application with mobile UX and UI structure, front-end logic and back-end APIs. Successfully completed programming training on Kodiri learning platform

HTML5 - CSS3 - JavaScript - ReacrJS - NodeJS - ExpressJS - MongoDB - Heroku - Github

🕨 Istituto Marangoni - London

BA (Hona) Fashion Design (2013 - 2016)

Course focused on the technical development of womenswear collections from initial research to garment design and production following industry standards.

Study of form, colour, pattern drafting and draping, and an accurate analysis of clothing manufacturing techniques as well as intensive market studies and principles of fashion business, brand identity, positioning and marketing. Through the course were explored techniques used within design and pattern making with a strong focus on sustainability and technology.

Following the personal interest on experimental design approaches and research on upcoming techniques, I have been involved in several in-house seminars as well as workshops to present relevant works to the university.

As part of the final year assessment, a personal capsule collection and brand was designed with experimental approached on intercultural juxtaposition of traditional fashion garments.

- * WESTERNIZATION was awarded as one of the 'Best Collections' of the year 2016 at Istituto Marangoni
- *The collection was showcased during the Graduate Fashion Week 2016
- *WESTERNIZATION was selected and published by ELLE (Uk) for the September 2016 issue

000

COMPETENCES

- Languages: Italian (native), English (fluent), Spanish (basic)
- Platforms: Shopify, Klaviyo Marketing, Mailchimp, Unleashed Management, Google Analytics
- Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, ReactJS
- Graphic Design: Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator and InDesign